

Daniel Lautenschlaeger

Electronics- & IT Student and Electrician

I am a technical passionate guy from down south of Germany, who is currently studying one semester User Experience Design at The Hague University of Applied Sciences. This gives me some nice insights about User Experience Design and provides a solid work basis to understand and cooperate better with Designers.

Work Experience

Eventhand & Electrician

EVENTCREW GMBH (KREUZLINGEN/SWITZERLAND)

December 2017 - Present

Building up & down of different events, theather set-ups and festivals Key contributions:

- · Wiring and setting up and down of lights on several big events
- Loading and unloading Trucks
- Building up and down of stages
- Setting up Lights and Speakers at the City-Theather of Zürich
- Building and wiring Traverses on and around stages

Electronics working student

INGUN PRÜFMITTELBAU GMBH (CONTANCE, GERMANY)

January 2017 - February 2018

Assisted electrical engineers and the whole development department with small tasks. The tasks varied from wiring switch cabinets to making excel lists

Key contributions:

- · Wired swith cabinets applying all the required DIN-ISO standards
- Helped developers with soldering and building up prototypes
- Did Warehouse work in the internal warehouse of the development department
- Created Excel lists and presentations to assistest the engineers

Service-technician for Smartphones and Tablets

ISOMEDIA GBR (STUTTGART, GERMANY)

June 2016 - August 2016

Repairing smartphones and tablets at the Samsung Customer Service plaza of Stuttgart, Germany

Key contributions:

- Did qualitative Repairing of several smartphone and tablet modells, which keeps with the official samsung warranty standard
- Responsible for the ESD-Checks of the working area

Education

The Hague University of Applied Sciences - The Hague, Netherlands

Bachelor of Science, 2018- Present

User Experience Design studies

University of Applied Sciences Constance - Constance, Germany

Bachelor of Engineering, 2016-2017

2 Semesters Electronics & IT studies

Vaccational school in cooporation with Tesat-Spacecom GmbH - Backnang, Germany

Apprenticeship (3,5 days work & 1,5 days school per week) + Evening high school, 2012-2016

Electrician for devices and systems + high school degree